Guide to the University Governance Records: Senate Records 2003-2013 RG3.8 RG 3.8 RG 3.8
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
University Governance Records: Senate Records
2003-2013
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University. University Senate.
RG 3.8
0.1 Linear Feet 55 MB, 462 files
This is a digital collection of University Senate records which include minutes, agendas and supporting documents.
Provenance
Transfer from Senate Archivist in Feb 2013
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Universtity Senate was formed in 1941. According to the University Senate Constitution published in 1980:
The Western Connecticut State University Senate exists by the will of the Faculty. Its existence is based upon the principle that to institute new or change existing policies concerning matters over which local university autonomy exists, it is necessary to have the approval of the University Administration, i.e., the President and his designated representative(s); the University Senate, if it wishes to act; and, the Student Government Association Senate, if it wishes to act. The University Senate also exists to act as a forum to discuss and, by resolution, to express its views on any topic of concern to the faculty.
Concerning policies over which local and University autonomy exists, the approval of the University Senate, if it wishes to act, is required. In the exercise of its authority over curriculum policy and curricular structure, requirements for degrees and granting of degrees, policies for recruitment, admission and retention of students, academic policies relating to students and other matters of campus community, and consistent with the principle of shared governance.
The Senate's bylaws stipulate that: All elections of the University Senate shall be held in the month of April. Officers of the Senate will be elected in May. The incoming Senate shall take office effective July 1, each year.
Senate officers shall consist of a President, a Vice President, a Secretary, and an Archivist to be elected before the end of each academic year by the incoming University Senate. The duties of the University Senate President shall be: To serve as the chief executive officer of the Senate; To preside at al1 meetings of the Senate; and, To appoint a parliamentarian. The duties of the University Senate Vice President shall be: to assume the duties of the President in the absence of or at the request of the President; to serve as Chairperson of the Senate Agenda Committee; to serve as a member of the Nominations and Elections Committee; and, to perform such other functions as may be assigned by the President. The duties of the University Senate Secretary shal1 be: to inform fully the faculty in writing of all decisions, in the form of generally complete minutes published as a special section of The Westconn Report; to communicate in writing with and to receive written replies from the President of the University as may be appropriate for policy establishment or change; to forward as appropriate Senate actions and recommendations to the appropriate body, standing committees, departments, et al. to maintain the tape recording of a Senate meeting until the formal approval of the minutes of that meeting has occurred.
The Senate shall meet the third Wednesday, at 3:30 p.m completed, on the following Wednesday at 3:30 p.m. of each academic month when the University is in session, unless the Senate President: a. cancels the meeting; or b. selects an alternate day and/or meeting time. [Senate Amended Oct. 17, 2001 (R-01 0905) and Administrative Approval Oct. 2001]
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of an electronic records transfer of minutes, agendas, and supporting documents from 2003-2012. A yearly records transfer of materials is scheduled for the fall of every academic year.
Universities and colleges.; Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; Minutes.; Agendas; Reports.; Western Connecticut State University.
- 2003
  - September 2003
    - Agenda, September 2003 (Item 1)
    - CUCAS AnnualReport, September 2003 (Item 2)
    - Graduate Council Bylaws- proposed revision, September 2003 (Item 3)
    - Minutes of theApril 2003 meeting, September 2003 (Item 4)
    - Minutes of theMay 2003 meeting, September 2003 (Item 5)
    - Minutes ofthe September 2003 meeting, October 2003 (Item 6)
    - President's response to SR-03-04-03, September 2003 (Item 7)
    - WCSU Strategic Plan, September 2003 (Item 8)
  - October 2003
    - Agenda, October 2003 (Item 9)
    - Center for Graphics Research - proposal, October 2003 (Item 10)
    - Student Life Committee annual report 2002-03, October 2003 (Item 11)
    - WCSU Strategic plan, October 2003 (Item 12)
    - Senate Minutes for October 2003 meeting, December 2003 (Item 13)
  - November 2003
    - Agenda, November 2003 (Item 14)
    - WCSU Strategic Plan, November 2003 (Item 15)
    - What do wewant in our new University president?, November 2003 (Item 16)
    - Senate Minutes for November 2003 meeting, December 2003 (Item 17)
  - December 2003
    - Agenda, December 2003 (Item 18)
    - Center for Graphics Research, December 2003 (Item 19)
    - Memo tosenators 12/12/2003, December 2003 (Item 20)
    - Presidential Search - letter from Chancellor Cibes, December 2003 (Item 21)
    - UPBC bylawsamendment, December 2003 (Item 22)
    - WCSU Strategic plan, December 2003 (Item 23)
    - Senate Minutes for December 2003 meeting, February 2004 (Item 24)
- 2004
  - February 2004
    - Agenda, February 2004 (Item 25)
    - Children and Pets at Work, February 2004 (Item 26)
    - GeneralEducation course labeling, February 2004 (Item 27)
    - Senate Minutes for February 2004 meeting, March 2004 (Item 28)
  - March 2004
    - Agenda, March 2004 (Item 29)
    - Children and Pets at Work - resolution, March 2004 (Item 30)
    - Enteringgrades online, March 2004 (Item 31)
    - Faculty Development and RecognitionCommittee (FDRS) by-laws revision, March 2004 (Item 32)
    - Previous drafts, March 2004 (Item 33)
    - WCSU Strategic Plan- final draft, March 2004 (Item 34)
    - Senate Minutes for March 2004 meeting, May 2004 (Item 35)
  - April 2004
    - Agenda, April 2004 (Item 36)
    - Center forProfessional Development - bylaws revision, April 2004 (Item 37)
    - Children andPets at Work, April 2004 (Item 38)
    - CSU Professorship Committee report, April 2004 (Item 39)
    - Document 1, April 2004 (Item 40)
    - Document 2, April 2004 (Item 41)
    - Enteringgrades online, April 2004 (Item 42)
    - History, April 2004 (Item 43)
    - Promotion and Tenure Committee annual report, April 2004 (Item 44)
    - Proposal to split CTAinto two departments, April 2004 (Item 45)
    - Westside NaturePreserve annual report, April 2004 (Item 46)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2004 meeting, September 2004 (Item 47)
  - May 2004
    - Academic Freedom, Tenure, and Promotion, May 2004 (Item 48)
    - Academic freedom, Tenure, and Promotion - Attachment, May 2004 (Item 49)
    - Agenda, May 2004 (Item 50)
    - Appeals procedure - Proficiency Skills requirement, May 2004 (Item 51)
    - Center forProfessional Development - bylaws revision, May 2004 (Item 52)
    - CPD Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 53)
    - D ECommittee Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 54)
    - EAPCommittee Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 55)
    - FDRC Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 56)
    - GraduateCouncil Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 57)
    - Human Subject Review - R and D Motion, May 2004 (Item 58)
    - MS andLPC Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 59)
    - Proposal to split CTAinto two departments, May 2004 (Item 60)
    - Q and A -IRB and IACUC, May 2004 (Item 61)
    - Rand DCommittee Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 62)
    - Student Life Committee Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 63)
    - UPBC Annual Report, May 2004 (Item 64)
    - UPBC Spending Plan, May 2004 (Item 65)
    - Senate Minutes for May 2004 meeting, September 2004 (Item 66)
  - September 2004
    - Academic Freedom, Tenure, and Promotion, September 2004 (Item 67)
    - Academic freedom, Tenure, and Promotion - Attachment, September 2004 (Item 68)
    - Agenda, September 2004 (Item 69)
    - Center forProfessional Development - bylaws revision, September 2004 (Item 70)
    - EAPCommittee Annual Report, September 2004 (Item 71)
    - Institute forHolistic Health Studies annual report, September 2004 (Item 72)
    - Proficiency requirement action plan, September 2004 (Item 73)
    - Proposal onProficiency Requirement Appeal, September 2004 (Item 74)
    - response to Senate Resolution R-04-03-03, September 2004 (Item 75)
    - Senate Minutes for September 2004 meeting, October 2004 (Item 76)
  - October 2004
    - Agenda, October 2004 (Item 77)
    - Center for Financial Forensics andInformation Security Proposal, October 2004 (Item 78)
    - CUCAS Annual report to the Senate 2003-2004, October 2004 (Item 79)
    - General Education Task Force Final Report, October 2004 (Item 80)
    - Guidelines on classes missedbecause of University-sponsored events (revised), October 2004 (Item 81)
    - IACUC Faculty Handbook statement, October 2004 (Item 82)
    - IRBresponse to R-04-05-03, October 2004 (Item 83)
    - Proposal onProficiency Requirement Appeal, October 2004 (Item 84)
    - WCSU Security Report October 2004 (Item 85)
    - Senate Minutes for October 2004 meeting, February 2005 (Item 86)
  - November 2004
    - Agenda, November 2004 (Item 87)
    - Center for Financial Forensics andInformation Security Proposal, November 2004 (Item 88)
    - Gen Ed report- Comments from the Philosophy dept, November 2004 (Item 89)
    - General Education Task Force FinalReport REVISED, November 2004 (Item 90)
    - IRBresponse to R-04-05-03, November 2004 (Item 91)
    - Resolutions regarding AAUP faculty evaluations, November 2004 (Item 92)
    - SGA resolution regarding the RogerSherman Debate Society, November 2004 (Item 93)
    - Student Life Committee Bylaws - proposed revision, November 2004 (Item 94)
    - Senate Minutes for November 2004 meeting, February 2005 (Item 95)
  - December 2004
    - "Fall break" resolution, December 2004 (Item 96)
    - Agenda, December 2004 (Item 97)
    - Foreign Language Department name change, December 2004 (Item 98)
    - ResolutionsRegarding AAUP faculty evaluations, December 2004 (Item 99)
    - Student Life Committee bylawsrevision, December 2004 (Item 100)
    - Student Life Committee resolution, December 2004 (Item 101)
    - Senate Minutes for December 2004 meeting, February 2005 (Item 102)
- 2005
  - February 2005
    - Agenda, February 2005 (Item 103)
    - Proposed bylaws of the Committee onGeneral Education, February 2005 (Item 104)
    - Reassignedtime for research, February 2005 (Item 105)
    - Research and Development Committee Bylaws Revision, February 2005 (Item 106)
    - Transfer admission guidelines, February 2005 (Item 107)
    - Senate Minutes for February 2005 meeting, April 2005 (Item 108)
  - March 2005
    - Agenda, March 2005 (Item 109)
    - Senate Minutes for March 2005 meeting (Item 110)
    - Proposed bylaws of the Committee onGeneral Education, March 2005 (Item 111)
    - Reassignedtime for research, March 2005 (Item 112)
    - Research and Development Committee Bylaws Revision, March 2005 (Item 113)
    - Senate Minutes for March 2005 meeting, April 2005 (Item 114)
  - April 2005
    - Academic Leave Committee, April 2005 (Item 115)
    - Agenda, April 2005 (Item 116)
    - Assessment Committee recommendations, April 2005 (Item 117)
    - Deadline for midterm grade entry into Banner, April 2005 (Item 118)
    - Pre-employment background verification - memo from HR, April 2005 (Item 119)
    - Pre-employment background verification policy, April 2005 (Item 120)
    - Summer Curriculum Related Activities - CUCAS Amendment, April 2005 (Item 121)
    - UPBC, April 2005 (Item 122)
    - Values and Vision - Perceptions and Directions, April 2005 (Item 123)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2005 meeting, September 2005 (Item 124)
  - May 2005
    - "Hybrid" courses, May 2005 (Item 125)
    - Admissions Committee Annual Report, May 2005 (Item 126)
    - Agenda, May 2005 (Item 127)
    - CPD Annual ReportREVISED, May 2005 (Item 128)
    - Deadline for midterm grade entry into Banner, May 2005 (Item 129)
    - EAPCommittee Annual Report, May 2005 (Item 130)
    - Excerpt from the minutes of the CSU BOT Finance andAdministration Committee - 2-25-05, May 2005 (Item 131)
    - Excerpt fromthe minutes of the CSU BOT meeting - 3-4-05, May 2005 (Item 132)
    - FacDevepmt and Reco Committee Annual Report, May 2005 (Item 133)
    - IACUC, May 2005 (Item 134)
    - Institute forHolistic Health Studies, May 2005 (Item 135)
    - Institutional Review Board issue- update, May 2005 (Item 136)
    - PAND T Committee Annual Report, May 2005 (Item 137)
    - Pre-employment background verification - memo from HR, May 2005 (Item 138)
    - Pre-employment background verification policy, May 2005 (Item 139)
    - Research and Development Committee Annual Report, May 2005 (Item 140)
    - Student Life Committee, May 2005 (Item 141)
    - UPBC, May 2005 (Item 142)
    - West Side NaturePreserve Annual report, May 2005 (Item 143)
    - Senate Minutes for May 2005 meeting, September 2005 (Item 144)
  - September 2005
    - Agenda, September 2005 (Item 145)
    - Committee onDistance Education Annual Report 2004-2005, September 2005 (Item 146)
    - CUCAS Annual Report 2004-2005, September 2005 (Item 147)
    - E-portfolio, September 2005 (Item 148)
    - Graduate CouncilAnnual Report 2004-2005, September 2005 (Item 149)
    - Senate Minutes for September 2005 meeting, November 2005 (Item 150)
  - October 2005
    - Academic Honesty Policy, October 2005 (Item 151)
    - Agenda, October 2005 (Item 152)
    - Hybrid Courses, DistanceEducation Committee, October 2005 (Item 153)
    - Institutional Review Board Bylaws, October 2005 (Item 154)
    - SummerCurriculum Grant Reports, October 2005 (Item 155)
    - UPTC Response to December,2004 Senate Resolutions, October 2005 (Item 156)
    - Senate Minutes for October 2005 meeting, February 2006 (Item 157)
  - November 2005
    - Agenda, November 2005 (Item 158)
    - GeneralEducation Course Approval Form, November 2005 (Item 159)
    - InstitutionalReview Board Annual Report, November 2005 (Item 160)
    - UPBC Planning Procedures and Routing Form, November 2005 (Item 161)
    - UPTC Response to December,2004 Senate Resolutions, November 2005 (Item 162)
    - Senate Minutes for November 2005 meeting, February 2006 (Item 163)
  - December 2005
    - Agenda, December 2005 (Item 164)
    - CUCAS Responseto Academic Honesty Policy, December 2005 (Item 165)
    - GeneralEducation Course Approval Form, December 2005 (Item 166)
    - StudentLife Response to Academic Dishonesty Policy, December 2005 (Item 167)
    - UPBC Planning Procedures and Routing Form, December 2005 (Item 168)
- 2006
  - February 2006
    - Agenda, February 2006 (Item 169)
    - Creation of a School of the Visual andPerforming Arts, February 2006 (Item 170)
    - Textbook Task Force Final Report, February 2006 (Item 171)
    - Senate Minutes for February 2006 meeting, April 2006 (Item 172)
  - April 2006
    - Agenda, April 2006 (Item 173)
    - AnimalRights Resolution, April 2006 (Item 174)
    - CUCAS/UPBC Resource Proposal, April 2006 (Item 175)
    - Faculty onCommittees, April 2006 (Item 176)
    - Institutional Review Board Bylaws, April 2006 (Item 177)
    - Reassigned Time for Research, April 2006 (Item 178)
    - Sheltered Smoking Zones, April 2006 (Item 179)
    - Summer Curriculum-Related Activities Funds, April 2006 (Item 180)
    - Senate Minutes for March 2006 meeting, May 2006 (Item 181)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2006 meeting, September 2006 (Item 182)
  - May 2006
    - Academic Honesty Policy, May 2006 (Item 183)
    - Agenda, May 2006 (Item 184)
    - UPTC AnnualReport, May 2006 (Item 185)
    - Senate Minutes for May 2006 meeting, September 2006 (Item 186)
  - September 2006
    - Agenda, September 2006 (Item 187)
    - AssessmentCommittee 2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 188)
    - CUCAS 2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 189)
    - General EducationCommittee 2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 190)
    - Graduate Council2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 191)
    - Institutional Review Board 2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 192)
    - Research &Development Committee 2005-2006 Annual Report, September 2006 (Item 193)
    - Senate Minutes for September 2006 meeting, December 2006 (Item 194)
  - October 2006
    - Agenda, October 2006 (Item 195)
    - EAP AnnualReport, October 2006 (Item 196)
  - November 2006
    - Agenda, November 2006 (Item 197)
    - CUCAS Bylaws, November 2006 (Item 198)
    - FacultyDevelopment & Recognition Committee Bylaws, November 2006 (Item 199)
    - General Education Committee Bylaws, November 2006 (Item 200)
    - Information Technology Committee Bylaws, November 2006 (Item 201)
    - MediaServices & Library Policy Committee Bylaws, November 2006 (Item 202)
  - December 2006
    - Academic Leave Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 203)
    - Admissions Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 204)
    - Admissions Committee Rationale, December 2006 (Item 205)
    - Assessment Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 206)
    - CELT Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 207)
    - Committee on General Education Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 208)
    - Distance Education Annual Report, December 2006 (Item 209)
    - Distance Education Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 210)
    - EAP Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 211)
    - General EducationCommittee Announcement, December 2006 (Item 212)
    - Graduate Council Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 213)
    - Promotion and Tenure Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 214)
    - Research and Development Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 215)
    - REVISED Agenda, December 2006 (Item 216)
    - Student Life Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 217)
    - Termination Hearing Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 218)
    - Working Conditions Committee Bylaws, December 2006 (Item 219)
    - Senate Minutes for December 2006 meeting, April 2007 (Item 220)
- 2007
  - April 2007
    - Academic LeaveCommittee Annual Report 2006-2007, April 2007 (Item 221)
    - Agenda, April 2007 (Item 222)
    - Eligibility for Dean's List for PT Students, April 2007 (Item 223)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2007 meeting, September 2007 (Item 224)
    - Senate Minutes for March 2007 meeting, September 2007 (Item 225)
  - May 2007
    - Agenda, May 2007 (Item 226)
    - Distance Education Annual Report 06-07, May 2007 (Item 227)
    - Distance Education Recommendations, May 2007 (Item 228)
    - Promotion andTenure Committee Annual Report 06-07, May 2007 (Item 229)
    - University Policy on Smoking, May 2007 (Item 230)
    - Senate Minutes for May 2007 meeting, September 2007 (Item 231)
  - September 2007
    - Agenda, September 2007 (Item 232)
    - AssessmentCommittee 2006-2007 Annual Report, September 2007 (Item 233)
    - Distance Education Committee Recommendations, September 2007 (Item 234)
    - Eligibility for Dean's list for part-time students, September 2007 (Item 235)
    - Revised smokingpolicy, September 2007 (Item 236)
    - Senate Minutes for September 2007 meeting, November 2007 (Item 237)
  - October 2007
    - Agenda, October 2007 (Item 238)
    - P & T Bylaw Revision, October 2007 (Item 239)
  - November 2007
    - Agenda, November 2007 (Item 240)
    - Common Course Numbering Plan, November 2007 (Item 241)
    - EAP 06-06 Annual Report, November 2007 (Item 242)
    - ScheduledCommon Hours, November 2007 (Item 243)
- 2008
  - February 2008
    - Agenda, February 2008 (Item 244)
    - Communications Dept Proposal on Grading Policy, February 2008 (Item 245)
    - General Education Committee Bylaws change, February 2008 (Item 246)
    - General Education Committee Bylaws change, February 2008 (Item 247)
    - Revision of GenEd Categories Descriptions for NWC and SS, February 2008 (Item 248)
  - March 2008
    - Agenda, March 2008 (Item 249)
    - CUCAS Bylawschange, March 2008 (Item 250)
    - EAP Bylaws change, March 2008 (Item 251)
    - Rational for EAP Bylaws change, March 2008 (Item 252)
  - April 2008
    - Agenda, April 2008 (Item 253)
    - CUCAS Bylawschange, April 2008 (Item 254)
    - EAP Bylaws change, April 2008 (Item 255)
    - General Education Committee Bylaw Change, April 2008 (Item 256)
    - Pand T Annual Report for 07/08, April 2008 (Item 257)
    - Rational for EAP Bylaws change, April 2008 (Item 258)
    - Westside NaturePreserve Annual Report for 07/08, April 2008 (Item 259)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2008 meeting, October 2008 (Item 260)
  - May 2008
    - Academic Leave Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 261)
    - Agenda, May 2008 (Item 262)
    - CGR Annual Reportfor 07/08, May 2008 (Item 263)
    - CUCAS AnnualReport for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 264)
    - CUCAS Bylawschange, May 2008 (Item 265)
    - EnrollmentManagement Committee Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 266)
    - Faculty Development Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 267)
    - General Education Committee Bylaw Change, May 2008 (Item 268)
    - GeneralEducation Committee Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 269)
    - Institute forHolistic Health Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 270)
    - Mediation Committee Bylaw Change, May 2008 (Item 271)
    - MediationCommittee Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 272)
    - Physical Working Conditions Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 273)
    - TerminationCommittee Annual Report for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 274)
    - UPBC AnnualReport for 07/08, May 2008 (Item 275)
    - Senate Minutes for May 2008 meeting, October 2008 (Item 276)
  - September 2008
    - Agenda, September 2008 (Item 277)
    - Distance Education Bylaws Change, September 2008 (Item 278)
    - Senate Minutes for September 2008 meeting, October 2008 (Item 279)
  - October 2008
    - Agenda, October 2008 (Item 280)
    - Senate Minutes for October 2008 meeting, November 2008 (Item 281)
  - November 2008
    - Agenda, November 2008 (Item 282)
    - Senate Minutes for November 2008 meeting, December 2008 (Item 283)
  - December 2008
    - Affirmative ActionGeneral Email, December 2008 (Item 284)
    - Agenda, December 2008 (Item 285)
    - EAP Bylaw Changeand Rational, December 2008 (Item 286)
    - Senate Minutes for December 2008 meeting, February 2009 (Item 287)
- 2009
  - February 2009
    - Agenda, February 2009 (Item 288)
    - Student Opinion Survey Committee Report, February 2009 (Item 289)
    - Senate Minutes for February 2009 meeting, March 2009 (Item 290)
  - March 2009
    - Agenda, March 2009 (Item 291)
    - Current Application for Sabbatic Leave, March 2009 (Item 292)
    - Revised Academic Leave Committee Bylaws, March 2009 (Item 293)
    - Revised Application for Sabbatic Leave, March 2009 (Item 294)
  - April 2009
    - Academic Leave Bylaws Change, April 2009 (Item 295)
    - Agenda, April 2009 (Item 296)
    - MediaServices and Library Policy Committee Bylaws Change, April 2009 (Item 297)
    - Promotion and Tenure Committee Bylaws Change, April 2009 (Item 298)
    - Sabbatic Leave Application Change, April 2009 (Item 299)
    - Senate Minutes for April 2009 meeting, September 2009 (Item 300)
  - May 2009
    - Academic Leave Annual Report for 08/09, May 2009 (Item 301)
    - Agenda, May 2009 (Item 302)
    - EnrollmentManagement Committee Annual Report for 08/09, May 2009 (Item 303)
    - Faculty Development Annual Report for 08/09, May 2009 (Item 304)
    - Fresh Start Policy Changes, May 2009 (Item 305)